Linda Walsh Jenkins Papers, 1975-1987
Sophia Smith Collection
Linda Walsh Jenkins Papers
1975-1987
Jenkins, Linda Walsh
MS 252 UUID:97b04f94-834f-460a-aa09-71c47f22e0b3
3 boxes (2.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Professor, theater; Actor. Source material and correspondence relating to her book Women in American Theatre; also scripts, ephemera, periodicals, essays, clippings, and correspondence related to women's theatres around the world; and correspondence, printed material, and drafts for the Women in the Performing Arts newsletter.
Biographical Note
Linda Walsh Jenkins was a tenured professor in the Theatre department at Northwestern University at the time this collection was donated. She was co-editor of Women in the American theatre: careers, images, movements: an illustrated anthology and sourcebook with Helen Kroch Chinoy (1981) and was an active member of the women's theatre community through the 1970s and 1980s. She had a son in 1971 and raised him as a single parent in Evanston, Il. No further biographical information is available.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Linda Walsh Jenkins Papers include source material and correspondence relating to her book Women in American Theatre. There are also scripts, ephemera, periodicals, essays, clippings, and correspondence related to women's theatres around the world, as well as correspondence, printed material, and drafts for the newsletter, Women in the Performing Arts.
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.
Linda Walsh Jenkins Papers donated her Papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1988 and 1989.
Feminist theater--United States--History--Sources; Women in the theater--United States--History--Sources; Women dramatists, American--20th century--Biography--Sources; Jenkins, Linda Walsh; Chinoy Helen Krich
Related materials are in the Helen Chinoy Papers in the Sophia Smith Collection and in the Faculty Files of the Smith College Archives.
- Women in Performing Arts newsletter
  - Background materials: notes, drafts, correspondence, manuscripts, press releases, mailing lists, printed material, and copies of newsletters 1975-82 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - General: correspondence, clippings, press releases, newsletters 1973-85 (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
  - Women's Studies (including Smith College): printed material, periodicals, correspondence, draft articles 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Assignment D": Correspondence, clippings and press releases 1978-81 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Suzanne Buton and Susan Stone 1975-82 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Joanne Hamlin (script) 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Women in American Theatre
  - Correspondence, contracts, and contacts list (includes Smith College, Sophia Smith Collection, Helen Chinoy, and Chinoy's Rally Day speech, Smith College 1983) 1974-86 (Box 1, Folder 13-17)
  - Correspondence, printed materials, clippings, and transcripts of interviews with Judith Malina, Peggy Shaw, and "R.B."'s interview with Lois Weaver 1984-87 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General: correspondence and printed materials 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General: source materials, correspondence, speeches, essays, drafts, mailings from theatres (includes Deborah Lubar scripts, transcript of Lillian Hellman and Bill Moyers interview 1971-88 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Mailing lists, contacts, correspondence, returned mail, and printed materials 1971-88 (Box 2, Folder 6-10)
- Scripts
  - "Finalists, top 5" (with correspondence from One Act Theatre and scripts by O-Lan Shepard, Denize Springer, Irene Oppenheim, Grace McKeaney, Susan Narus 1977-81, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "One Act Plays, numbers 1-16 (Susan Kennedy, Kitty Tsui, Tobey Chappell, Toni Press, Sylvia Bigelow, Annawin Shamas, June Griffin, Kathleen Magill, Theresa Mayer Hammond, Susan E. Spoth, Janice Penkalski 1979-81, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
    - Marijane Datsun: "Last Acts," press releases and clippingsn.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Martha Boesing: 2 scripts 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous
  - "Old Wives Tale": script by Linda Jenkins, with correspondence with Lilith, a Woman's Theatre 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Rated X" (film): correspondence, abstract, and endorsements 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Nancy Rhodes: correspondence and copy of "A Study on Employment Discrimination Against Women Playwrights and Directors in Non Profit Theatre" 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Christine Westwood (Women's theatre in Australia): correspondence, press releases and ephemera 1977-78 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, mailings, press releases, biographies, posters, photographs, playbills, and other printed material from theatre groups (includes Washington American Feminist Theatre, Chicago Theatre Group Inc., American Theatre Association, At The Foot of the Mountain, Plutonium Players, Women's Collage Theatre, Women's International Theatre Alliance, Lilith, a Woman's Theatre, Theatre Rhinocerous) 1976-89 (Box 2, Folder 19-24)
  - Correspondence, mailings, press releases, biographies, posters, photographs, playbills, and other printed material from theatre groups 1976-89 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - Dance: printed material (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous clippings 1977-80 (Box 3, Folder 8)